Rehan Guha

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India



rehanguha29@gmail.com



+919874223189



linkedin.com/in/rehanguha

Summary

To talk about myself is a bit of a challenge for me as I more comfortable while talking about my work and discussing about Philosophy & Science.

Let me start by giving a simple introduction about my work. I am a Senior Machine Learning Researcher presently employed by product based company. I have worked in several ML projects mainly dealing with Optimization Problems, Explainable AI, Deep Learning, Imbalance Classification, et cetera...

I am also the author of a book "Machine Learning Cookbook with Python" published by BPB publications. I have been part multiple publications through Journals and Open Publications, along with this I have few applied patents to my name.

Recently I was invited by Arizona State University to be a part of their team participating in CPS challenge 2020 funded by National Science Foundation(NSF), USA and sponsored by NASA. I have also conducted multiple workshops, seminars in this field of research for various universities and made contributions to Open Source Software as well.

Experience

OPRAMATI Senior Researcher

Pramati Technologies Private Limited

Oct 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

imaginea Senior Data Scientist

Imaginea Technologies Inc.

Oct 2019 - Present (1 year 5 months +)

== VERANA ==

Role: Managed the Data Science team of 2 including myself from Imaginea. Actively worked on their clinical dataset for increasing their coverage and accuracy for their existing scripts.

Stack: Python, PySpark, AWS, NLP

We worked on some of their existing code and increased their accuracy and coverage percentage. We developed an address extraction script from a given document using NLP.

== BAIN ==

Role: Responsible for analyzing the CLV and building a Data Analytics dashboard.

Stack: Tableau, Python, Microsoft Excel

The project involves analyzing the survey data and figuring out the CLV. It also entails creating a Tableau Dashboard that analyzes all the features in a single dashboard.

Book Author

BPB

Aug 2019 - Nov 2020 (1 year 4 months)

I am thrilled to announce finally a year-long endeavour came to an end.

A Cookbook that will help you implement Machine Learning algorithms and techniques by building real-world projects.

Key Features

- Learn how to handle an entire Machine Learning Pipeline supported with adequate mathematics.
- Create Predictive Models and choose the right model for various types of Datasets.
- Learn the art of tuning a model to improve accuracy as per Business requirements.
- Get familiar with concepts related to Data Analytics with Visualization, Data Science and Machine Learning.



Participant

National Science Foundation (NSF)

May 2020 - Jun 2020 (2 months)

2020 CPS Challenge "SoilScope -- Mars edition":

Mars 2020 inspired mission scenario for the 2020 NSF CPS Challenge will be a two-week virtual event, emulating an autonomous probe deployment science mission by a rover and drone duo, at the Jezero crater landing site.

Organizer:

Arizona State University, NASA

OPRAMATI Researcher

Pramati Technologies Private Limited

Oct 2018 - Sep 2019 (1 year)

imaginea Data Scientist

Imaginea Technologies Inc.

Oct 2018 - Sep 2019 (1 year)

== RPX Corporation ==

Role: Handled Litigation Likelihood (LitLikelihood) module of the project – from data analysis to production deployment.

Stack: Python, Flask, Gunicorn, Machine Learning (LGBM)

In this project, the data (~12M records) requires a lot of transformation where some major errors have been observed leading to a drastic improvement in the prediction accuracy. Therefore, LightGBM has been used here and the model is accepted by the client as well.

Other projects:-

- Imbalance Learning with Probabilistic Scoring with Binary Classification
- LDA Topic Clustering

Associate Software Engineer

Accenture

Jan 2017 - Sep 2018 (1 year 9 months)

I am working as a Machine Learning Developer at Accenture for multiple Research projects, and few of the research projects won awards and it has been considered as product by the company.

Work Experience on:

- 1) Machine Learning
- 2) Python
- 3) AngularJS

Projects:

- 1) Financial Service Development Project (Quartz Development) (Full Time, Managed team size of 2)
- 2) Self Learning Credit Approval System (Part time, 3 months)
- 3) Al Model Based Risk Management (Part time, 4 months)
- 4) Ship and Air Cargo Routing (Part time, 2 months)
- 5) Digital Content and Transaction Management using an Artificial Intelligence (AI) based Communication System (Part time, 3 months)
- 6) Routing System for Car Pool and Drop for the Employees (Part time, 3months)

Founder

PixRead

Dec 2016 - Sep 2018 (1 year 10 months)

One of a kind OCR & 2D Codes (QR Code, Bar Code etc) search engine where the extracted text will be searched over a search engine. This will ease all the users to take a picture (which has text) from a device and search over different search engines.

Anyone willing to contribute can contact me.

Bounty Hunter

HackerOne

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 8 months) Found and Resolved Bugs for: 1) Zomato

📟 Technical Associate

Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata Aug 2015 - Dec 2015 (5 months) SEO, Technical Troubleshooter, Web Development (Wordpress)

Education



👔 Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

Deep Learning (AICTE approved FDP course), Computer Science

2019 - 2019

Level: Postgraduate

Jul-Oct 2019 (12 Week course)

This is an AICTE approved FDP course

🕎 Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata

Bachelor of Computer Application, Computer Science

pelhi Public School, Ruby Park

All India Senior School Certificate Examination, Computer Science 2003 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications

- **G** Google for Education Basics Exam Google
- Python for Data Science IBM
- Build Your Own Chatbot Level 1 IBM
- Data Science Foundations Level 1 IBM
- Applied Data Science with Python Level 2 IBM
- Machine Learning with Python IBM
- Deep Learning Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur NPTEL 19CS54S41212108

Skills

Deep Learning • Machine Learning • Research • Artificial Intelligence • Algorithms • Data Analysis • Product Development • Financial Services • Credit Risk • Image Processing

Honors & Awards

- Student Performance Award Institute of Engineering & Management, Kolkata
- Accenture Celebrates Excellence Accenture

May 2018 Category - Innovation Award type - Individual

Accenture Celebrates Excellence - Accenture

Nov 2017 Category - Client and Customer Award type - Team

Accenture Celebrates Excellence - Accenture

Aug 2018

Category - Innovation Award type - Team



Runners-Up - National Science Foundation (NSF) & Arizona State University (ASU) Jul 2020

In this challenge, we use a drone to search for and locate a soil probe. The drone picks up the probe and takes it to a drop-off location. Then, the drone must autonomously return to a rover and land in its trunk. This was accomplished using Rtabmap, a SLAM package used to estimate the position and velocity states of the rover with visual odometry and our own tailor-made Kalman Filter conflated with GPS based state estimation and the visual odometry based states.